A Finding Aid to the Bernard Harper Friedman papers,1926-2011, bulk 1943-2010, in the Archives of American Art AAA.friebern
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1946-2011; Series 2; 14.7 Linear feet Boxes 1-15
  - Kolin, Oscar, 1982-1987 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Koltun, Susie, 1997-2010 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Kostelanetz, Richard, 1995-2002 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Kotuk, Maggie, 2002-2005 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Krasner, Lee, 1955-2007 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Kreznar, Richard and Nancy Lew Lee, 1979-2008 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Kronen, James, 1976-1979 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Kronholtz, Jan, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Krupp, Jane, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Kunitz, Stanley and Elise Asher, 1946-2004 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - L, Miscellaneous, 1953-2010 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
  - Lader, Larry, 2002-2006 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Lake, Fred E., 1960-1971 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Landau, Ellen, 1987-1990 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Landmark Gallery, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Lassaw, Denise, 2005-2006 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Lassaw, Ibram, 1973-2002 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Lau, Rex, 1990-2010 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Lauder, Leonard A., 1987-2003 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Leader, Graham, 1994-2002 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Learsy, Raymond, 1976-2007 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Leary, Timothy, 1961-1966 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    photocopies
  - Leavin, Margo, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - LeBoutille, Pam, 1981-2007 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - le Brocquy,Louis and Ann Madden, 1981-2006 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Lederman, Stephanie Brody, 2001-2010 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Lee, Nancy Lew, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Lennon, Peter, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Leslie, Alfred, 1969-1999 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Levin, Gail, 1994-2010 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Levine, Ned, 1965-1976 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Levine, Seymour, 1952-1987 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Levinson, Daniel, 1972-1977 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Lewis, R.W.B., 1974 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Liber, Edward, 1990-2003 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Libertson, David, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Little, Brown and Company, 1975-1981 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Little Movies, Inc., 1962-1963 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Loeb, Albert, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Loggia, Marjorie, 1984-1986 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Long Island University, 1998-2002 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Long, Robert, 2004-2006 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Lord, Ruth, 2003-2005 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Sterling Lord Literistic, Inc., 2002-2005 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Lords Gallery, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Lowenstein, Allard K., 1968-1972 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Lukashok, Martin and Marilyn, 1955-2007 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - M, Miscellaneous, 1950-2008 (Box 9, Folder 40-42)
  - Maartens, Marc E., 1981-1990 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - MacFadden Books, 1963-1965 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Macklowe, Harry, 1985-2005 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Madlener, Jörg, 1987-1995 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Magriel, Paul, 1977-1980 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Majdrakoff, Ivan, 1963-1991 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Malin, Irving, 1976-1982 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Mandel, Claude and Maggie, 1995-2009 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Harace Mann School, 1955-2009 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Marca-Relli, Conrad, 1965-2000 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Marks, Matthew S., 1980-2004 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Marlborough Gallery, Inc., 1964-1976 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Martinos, Mr. and Mrs., 1954-1955 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Maseland, Mercedes, 1961-1965 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Mathews, Harry, 1971-1992 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Matter, Mercedes, 1970-1973 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Maxwell, Mary, 2006-2008 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Maybank, Celestine, 1967-1969 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Mc Conkey, Jim, 1984-2000 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Mc Darrah, Fred W., 1984-2000 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - McEwen, Rory, 1969-2003 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Co., 1952-1982 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - McIntosh, Mavis, 1957-1959 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - McKee, David, 1975-2006 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - McKee, Margo, 2003-2008 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - McQuade, Molly, 1986-1995 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Edwin Mellen Press, 1977-1997 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Meneeley, Edward, 1967-2006 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Meridian Books, Inc., 1961 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Mernit, Billy, 1982-2008 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Metcalf, Jim and Anna, 1960-2003 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Metropolitan Musuem of Art, 1975-2006 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Meyer, Steven, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Michaelis, David, 1979-2010 (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
  - Middleman, Raoul, 1966-2010 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Milazzo, Richard, 1990-2009 (Box 10, Folder 11-12)
  - Miller, Flora, 1971-1986 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    Flora Miller also corresponded with Friedman when she was named Flora Biddle and Flora Irving.
  - Moloney, Philip J., 1960-1993 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Montemaggi, Linda K., 1974-1976 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Mooney, Michael, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Mostel, Raphael, 1996-2001 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Motherwell, Robert, 1979-1991 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Motherwell, Robert and Helen Frankenthaler, 1956-1979 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Mozel, Claire, 1975-1985 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Museum of American Folk Art, 1979-2007 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1956-2009 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Music Publishers Holding Corp., 1961 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Myers, David, 1958-1966 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Myers, John Bernard, 1954-1968 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - N, Miscellaneous, 1952-2010 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Namuth, Hans, 1970-1984 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Nathanson, Richard, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - The Nation, 1958-1960 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Nedelkoff, Robert, 2004-2005 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - The New American Library of World Literature, Inc., 1963-1965 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - New American Review, 1968-1972 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - The New-York Historical Society, 1958-1976 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - New York Review of Books, 1973-1981 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - New York Studio School, 1970-1997 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - The New York Times, 1953-2010 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - The New Yorker, 1954-2010 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Newman, Arnold, 1973-1996 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Newman, Barnett and Annalee, 1957-1960 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - The Barnett Newman Foundation, 1982-2007 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Newman, Christine, 1983-1986 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Newman, John, 2006-2009 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Newport Harbor Art Musuem, 1985-1988 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Nicholas, Stephen W., 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Nimkin, Jean and Bill, 1958-2009 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Norman, Dorothy, 1958-1975 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Norton, Peter, 1995-2008 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Noselson, Kalman, 1956-1997 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Noselson, Maurice B., 1962-1973 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Nossiter, Cal Kolbe, 1961-1985 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Nye, Tim, 1988-2010 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - O, Miscellaneous, 1958-2002 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Oftedal, Dale and Lynn Cullington, 2005-2011 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Oldenburg, Claes, 1978-1989 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Oresman, Donald and Patricia, 1999-2005 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Oscarson, Victoria, 1983-2006 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Ossorio, Alfonso, 1961-1990 (Box 11, Folder 12-13)
  - Alfonso Ossorio Estate and Foundation, 1991-2003 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Ossorio, Robert, 1968-1986 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - P, Miscellaneous, 1958-2008 (Box 11, Folder 16-18)
  - The Pace Gallery, 1976-2001 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Padgett, Ron, 1973-2008 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - The Paris Review, 1971-1998 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Parker, Ray and Denise, 1969-1990 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - The Partisan Review, 1960-1970 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Patterson, Cristina and Keith, 1962-1986 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - PEN, 1973-2010 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Perl, Jed, 2006-2009 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Peters, Robert, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Phildadelphia Musuem of Art, 1980-2005 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Phillips, Lewis, 1963-1998 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Phillips, Louis, 1990-2006 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Planned Parenthood, 2005-2008 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Playbill, 1957-1958 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Poet Lore, 1993-2009 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - The Poetry Center, 1976-1981 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Poets and Writers Magazine, 1974-2010 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Pollock, Jackson and Lee Krasner, 1955-2007 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    mostly Lee Krasner
  - The Pollock-Krasner Foundation, Inc., 1990-2001 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - The Pollock-Krasner House and Study Center, 1988-2010 (Box 11, Folder 38-39)
  - Pollock, Lawrence S. and Shirley, 1962-2007 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Porter, David, 1983-1995 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Potter, Jeffrey and Priscilla Bowden, 1982-2005 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Power, Allen, 1956-1960 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Powers, John G., 1972-1973 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Praeger, David, 1959-1988 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Prashker, Betty, 1982-1984 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Prince, Frank, 1977-1979 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Prinzhorn Collection, 1986-1989 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Provincetown Fine Arts Work Center, 1969-1987 (Box 11, Folder 49-51)
  - Provincetown Poets, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Pushcart Press, 1984-1994 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Q, Miscellaneous, 1974-1979 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Quarterly Review of Literature, 1966-1973 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - R, Miscellaneous, 1954-2010 (Box 12, Folder 5-7)
  - Rabkin, Dorothy and Leo, 1970-2008 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Ralli, Susanna, 2006-2009 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Raynard, Pat and Louis Phillips, 1966-1973 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Rand, Ronald, 2004-2008 (Box 12, Folder 11-13)
  - Random House, Inc., 1960-1993 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Rapée, Joellen Hall and George, 1966-2006 (Box 12, Folder 15-17)
    Joellen Hall was once Mrs. Jon Schueler; additional correspondence with her is found in the Schueler file.
  - Rapée, Joellen Hall - Estate of, 1997-2007 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Rattray, David, 1983-2002 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Rattray, Helen, 2002-2007 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Rattray, Mary, 1994-2006 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Rawlings, John, 1954-1958 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Reich, Murray, 1977-2009 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Reichert, Stephen A., 2007-2009 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Reid, Alastair and Mary, 1960-1994 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Reis, Becky, 1958-1960 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Richenburg, Robert and Margaret Kerr, 1983-2006 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Rizzo, George, 2005-2009 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Robertson, Bryan, 1962-2001 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Robinson, Bennett, 1995-2003 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Rose, Daniel, 1975-2003 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Rosen, Seymour, 1981-2009 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Rosenfeld, Michael, 1993-2007 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Rozenkranz, Robert, 1998-2001 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Ross, Clifford, 1955-1997 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Ross, Lillian, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Rosset, Barney, 1988-2008 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Roth, Daryl, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Roth, Philip, 1974-1998 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Rothschild, Judith, 1977-1991 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Rothschild, Robert F. and Maurine, 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Ruddick, Dorothy, 2004-2005 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Ryan, Kyra, 2002-2005 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - S, Miscellaneous, 1952-2008 (Box 12, Folder 44-49)
  - Saffian, Jennifer Pinto, 1991-1996 (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - St. James Press, 1982-1987 (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - St. Martin's Press, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 52)
  - Salvesen, Magda (Mrs. Jon Schueler), 1975-2010 (Box 13, Folder 1-4)
  - Sandler, Irving, 1970-2001 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Sanger, Linda, 1982-2011 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Scarpitta, Salvatore and Dana, 1972-2007 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Scahaefer, Abby, 1975-1981 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Schaefer, Charles L. and Paula, 1958-2006 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Scheuer, Steven, 1999-2005 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Schoelkopf, Robert, 1973-1986 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Schueler, Jon, 1956-1992 (Box 13, Folder 12-18)
  - Schulberg, Budd, 1984-2009 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Schwartz, Ronnie, 1984-2009 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Scott, Robert A., 1991-2009 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Seaver, Jeannette and Richard, 1972-2009 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Seebohm, Caroline, 1995-1997 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Seely, Robert D. and Marcia, 1960-1999 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Seidman, Peter, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Serendipity Books, 1977-1980 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Shadlen, Conrad, 1998-1999 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Shepard, Judith and Martin, 1991-1998 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Silver, Joan and Ron, 1993-2007 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Silver, Walter, 1959-1994 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Simon and Schuster, 1962-1992 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Simon, Sidney, 1975-1997 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Singer, Clifford, 1975-1981 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Singsen, Hope, 2002-2003 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Skillings, Roger, 1971-2010 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Skodnick, Roy, 2000-2001 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Slate, Barbara and Richard Minsky, 2004-2011 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Slivka, David, 1958-2010 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Slivka, Rose, 1958-2001 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Smith, Carol, 1977-1999 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Smithsonian Instituiton - Archives of American Art, 1972-2009 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Smithsonian Institution - National Collection of Fine Art, National Museum of American Art, National Portrait Gallery, Renwick Gallery, Smithsonian Institution Press, 1978-2009 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Soderman, Doris Flodin, 1993-1995 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Solinger, Betty Ann, 1997-2003 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Solodar, John, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - Solomon, Michael, 1996-2004 (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - Sotheby's, 1987-1993 (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - Spielberg, Peter, 1976-1983 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Staebell, Diane, 1961-1962 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Steinman, Charles, 1989-1990 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Stephens, Michael, 1973-1997 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Stern, Gerd, 2006-2008 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Still, Clyfford, 1956-1974 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Stoetzel, Kelly and Lee, 1998-2000 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - C. A. Stonehill, Inc., 1969 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Stout, Myron, 1972-1987 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Straight, Beatric, 1977-1981 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Strand, Mark, 1970-1976 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Strong-Cuervas, Elizabeth, 1997-2005 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Stuhlmann, Gunther, 1962-2011 (Box 14, Folder 13-19)
  - Sukenick, Ronald, 1975-1997 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Sullivan, Patrick, 1979-1984 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Swoger, Arthur, 1996-1997 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - T, Miscellaneous, 1956-2010 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Taylor, Donald MacKay, 1978-2000 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Thévoz, Michael, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Thomas, Evan, 1997-1999 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Tilton, Jack, 1984-2007 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Tompkins, Calvin, 1980-2010 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Tovey, Tamara, 1974-2006 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Trachtman, Paula, 2003-2009 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - TriQuarterly, 1967-1975 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Turner, Steve, 1996-2004 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - U, Miscellaneous, 1961-2009 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - U. N. Plaza Health Club, 1988-2007 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Uris Brothers Foundation, Inc., 1974-1996 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Uris, Percy, 1963-1974 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Urso, Josette, 1990-2009 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Ursus Books, 1993-2006 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - V, Miscellaneous, 1959-2005 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Vaid, Krishna, 1994-1995 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Van Cleef, Jabez, 1967-1995 (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Van Dalen, Michael, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Vanderberg, Albert, 1966-1977 (Box 14, Folder 43-45)
  - Vanderberg, Albert, 1977-2003 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
  - The Viking Press, 1964-1981 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Violett, Ellen, 1997-2005 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Vogue, 1966-1983 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Vollmer, Ruth, 1960-1967 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - W, Miscellaneous, 1958-2009 (Box 15, Folder 7-8)
  - Watson, Berta, 1978-1985 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Wallace, Thomas C., 1998-2005 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Walling, Odette, 1963-1964 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Wasserman, Bernard, 1985-2000 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Wasserman, Helene, 1990-2003 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Weil, Andrew T., 1968-2001 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Weil, Leon J. and Mabel, 1961-2008 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Weil, Stephen E., 1974-1975 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Weinstein, Frank, 1981-1984 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Weinstein, Henry T., 1958-1996 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Weiss, Ania, 1982-2009 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Weissman, Julian, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Westermann, Joanna Beale, 1963-1982 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Wexler, Jerry and Jean, 1988-2008 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Wheeler, David, 1974-1988 (Box 15, Folder 23-24)
  - Whelk's Walk Press, 1998-1999 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - The Whitechapel Art Gallery, 1965-1972 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Williams, Jonathan, 1958-1990 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Wilson, Mr. and Mrs. Edmund, 1961-1974 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Windham, Donald, 1981-1995 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Wittenborn Art Books, Inc., 1960-1991 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - WNET Thirteen, 1979-1987 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Wolf, Van, 1961-1972 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Woodworth, James, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - World Publishing Company, 1964-1969 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Wyndham, Francis, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Y-Z, Miscellaneous, 1981-2012; 1981-2010 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Yarborough, Bert, 1984-2010 (Box 15, Folder 37-38)
  - Yau, John, circa 1979-1999 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Yekati, Nico, 1986-2010 (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - YM-YWHA Poetry Center, 1966-1971 (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - Yohn, Tim, 1975-1989 (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Zamaryanov, Vladislav and Kira, 2006-2008 (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - Zeisler, Richard S., 1962-1990 (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - Zinberg, Dorothy, 1965-1990 (Box 15, Folder 45)
  - Zwart, Joyce and Dan Willis, 1996-1997 (Box 15, Folder 46)
- Interviews, 1969-2001; Series 3; 0.2 Linear feet Box 15
  Transcripts of interviews conducted by C. Darrow with B. H. Friedman, his daughter and wife for the Yale University School of Medicine "Adult Development Study" are photocopies. Accompanying the interviews is a preliminary version of "Time of Transition: The Male in the Mid-Life Decade," an article by Maggie Scarf for the June 1972 issue of McCall's Magazine. A note by Friedman indicates "Charlotte Darrow gave me this material some of which was used in her thinly disguised 'portrait' of me in The Seasons of a Man's Life, Knopf 1978."
  - "Adult Development Study" (Box 15)
    - Interview #1, C. Darrow and B. H. Friedman (transcript), 1969 September 1 (Box 15, Folder 47)
    - Interview #2, C. Darrow and B. H. Friedman (transcript), 1969 September 3 (Box 15, Folder 48)
    - Interview #3, C. Darrow and B. H. Friedman (transcript), 1969 September 6 (Box 15, Folder 49)
    - Interview #4, C. Darrow and B. H. Friedman (transcript), 1969 September 25 (Box 15, Folder 50)
    - Interview #5, C. Darrow and B. H. Friedman (transcript), 1969 September 25 (Box 15, Folder 51)
    - Follow-up Interview #1, C. Darrow and Daisy Friedman (transcript), 1970 November 10 (Box 15, Folder 52)
    - Final Interview - Follow-up, B. H. Friedman and C. Darrow (transcript), 1971 February 5 (Box 15, Folder 53)
    - Interview, C. Darrow and Abby Friedman (Mrs. Robert ( sic); transcript), 1971 January 28 (Box 15, Folder 54)
    - Memo to Development Study Participants and Related Article by Maggie Scarf, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 55)
  - Mrs. Flora Miller Irving and B. H. Friedman on "Not for Artists Only" discussing Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney, 1979; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 15, Folder 56)
  - B. H. Friedman interviewed by Bonnie Grice, "The Song is You," WPBX Radio, 2001; 1 Sound discs (CD) (Box 15, Folder 57)
- Writings, 1940s-2010; Series 4; 8 Linear feet Boxes 16-23
  Writings by B. H. Friedman include novels, plays, short stories, poems, articles, monographs, and criticism. Over time, many pieces were reworked. Sometimes titles changed or were reused; occasionally, prose became a play or short stories were greatly expanded. Among the published versions of Friedman's writings are two books and some short stories with no corresponding manuscript material. This series also includes recordings (3 videocassettes (VHS), 2 sound cassettes, and 1 sound reel) of lectures by Friedman and panel discussions in which he participated. Writings by other authors include the text of a lecture presented by John Cage at Cal Tech.
  Friedman's writings are arranged in three categories - manuscripts and drafts, published versions, lectures and panel discussions - and within each group are alphabetized by title. Writings by others are arranged alphabetically by author. Subject files (Series 6) contain additional writings by Friedman and others.
  - By B. H. Friedman, 1940s-2010 (Box 16)
    - Manuscripts and Drafts (Box 16)
      - "Almost a Profile", circa 1980s (Box 16, Folder 1-3)
      - "Ampersand", circa 2007 (Box 16, Folder 4)
        Written with Flora Biddle
      - Appreciation of Property, circa 1985-circa 2000s (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - "Art World Details: Journal Excerpts, 1952-1992", circa 1992-2000s (Box 16, Folder 6-8)
      - "An Award", circa 1985-2000s (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - Beauty Business: A Farce in Two Acts, circa 1987-circa 1991 (Box 16, Folder 10-12)
      - Between the Flags (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - "Blind Date", circa 1985-circa 2000s (Box 16, Folder 14)
      - Book Reviews, 1960s-1990s (Box 16, Folder 15)
      - Case History: A Play in Two Acts, circa 1990s (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - Circles, circa 1962 (Box 16, Folder 17-18)
      - The Critic: A Play in Two Acts inspired by Moliere's 'The Misanthrope' (Box 16, Folder 19)
      - Criticism, circa 1962-circa 1970s (Box 16, Folder 20)
      - "Criticism, Volume I", 1965-1968 (Box 16, Folder 21-22)
      - "Criticism, Volume II", 1965-1968 (Box 16, Folder 23-24)
      - "Diptych, Part One: Almost a Profile", circa 1950s (Box 16, Folder 25)
      - "Diptych: Who's Who", circa 1950s (Box 16, Folder 26)
      - Early Writings (Box 17)
        - "Let's Have a Wonderful Time", circa 1940s-circa 1950s (Box 17, Folder 1)
        - Poems, circa 1940s-circa 1950s (Box 17, Folder 2)
        - Poems and Short Stories, circa 1940s-circa 1950s (Box 17, Folder 3)
        - Short Stories, circa 1940s-circa 1950s (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - "An Education at Paradise Point", 1982-1983 (Box 17, Folder 5-8)
      - "Eros and Psyche" (another version is titled Sex and Character), 2000 (Box 17, Folder 9-11)
      - Everyone's Afraid of Thomas Wolfe (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - "Flora's Two-Part Invention" (also called "Two Part Invention"), 2008 (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - "Fragments of an Occupational Autobiography, circa 1957-circa 1973 (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - "Happy Birthday, Dear Norman, Happy Birthday to Me: A Retrospective of the Party", circa 1973 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Heart of a Boy: A Play in Two Acts, circa 1993 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Heart of a Boy: A Screenplay, circa 1996 (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - "Honeymoon", circa 1950s (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - "Hope's Story", circa 1985-circa 2000s (Box 17, Folder 19-21)
      - In Search of Luigi Pirandello: A Play inTwo Acts (another version is titled My Small Self: A Play in 10 Scenes, circa 1986 (Box 17, Folder 22)
      - "It's Only Money", circa 1968-circa 1973 (Box 17, Folder 23-24)
      - "Journal of an Anonymous Businessman" (Box 17, Folder 25-26)
      - "The Kleptomaniac," revised (other versions are titled My Case Rests and "Things"), 1988 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - "Lanes", circa 1985-circa 2000s (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - "The Making of a Writer", circa 1975-circa 1984 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Married Moments Synopsis, circa 2005 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Married Moments, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - "The Message in the Bottle: Objects in Bottles, Mostly American, Religious and Turn-of-the-Century" with illustrations (Box 18, Folder 6-9)
      - "A Mini-Vacation to a Mini-Paradise", 2010 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - "Mushrooms", circa 1962 (Box 18, Folder 11-13)